A trailblazing leader in government,
business, and philanthropy.
>> A former presidential adviser to Donald
Trump, Dina Pal McCormack joined Meta
Platforms as president and vice
chairwoman.
>> She'll help lead the company's massive
AI expansion, including data centers,
investments, and global partnerships.
>> Powell McCormack's background is exactly
where Meta's new bottlenecks are.
>> There is a transformation in humanity
coming. Nothing can stop that now with
this technology. 3.5 billion people
every day are on Meta. I think we all
know that the next three years could be
the whole game. Women are the secret
sauce.
How about that?
>> Please welcome Dena Powell McCormick.
see you. Thanks for coming out.
>> Hey, good to see you. All right, good to
see you.
>> How are you?
Dina, thank you for being here. Um, you
know, we were just finishing up a
conversation with Satcha about how do we
tell the story about the benefit of data
centers and what they're doing to
communities and why they're actually net
economically positive. And I know you so
I'm going to get right into it because I
know you actually have a video on this.
Do you want to just start with your
video? Would that be okay?
>> That'd be great. I mean, I just want to
say so psyched uh to be at the All-In
Summit, first time to speak, and as long
as this episode and panel gets way more
listeners and views than Senator
McCormix did when he came on, I'll be
very, very happy with that. So, now we
can now we can roll the tape. No
competition.
>> Good. We'll put it on Poly Market. Let's
watch the video.
>> Richmond Parish was the place that
opportunity forgot about.
I've grown up here my whole life and
I've seen a lot of people move away
looking for work, including my son.
What you were hearing a lot lately was
there's nothing here for us anymore.
We knew that having a data center would
give us an industry here that we haven't
had before. That's a huge investment in
our community.
We started this business simply because
meta was coming.
We thought we had hit it big when we got
to cater for 40 people. Now we do 400 a
week.
>> Since Meta came to town, we've hired
more employees.
>> A multi-billion dollar capital
investment like the one that Meta is
making in Richland Parish is it was
transformative. It's extremely exciting
to attract and retain quality teachers.
So, when I first got the news about the
bonus, it was jaw-dropping. My mouth was
literally wide open.
We're not in it for the money. We're
teachers because it's in our heart. But
the bonus has been extremely helpful.
>> With the investment that Meta has made
in our community, now we can do a better
job of taking care of our home.
>> I do feel a lot of hope for the future
of my students. It gives them the
opportunity they never thought that they
would have.
And I would say one of the biggest
things is people coming back home.
>> You know, the future's happening here
and happening now.
>> You have some folks from the video here.
>> I do. Can come on out. Come on out,
>> Sheldon. and Susan, we have the
superintendent
from that video, the superintendent in
Richland Parish.
>> Thanks for joining us. Pleasure.
>> Hi, sir.
>> Thanks for joining us. Hi, how are you?
Come on down.
>> Good to meet you. How are you?
>> Thank you for being here.
>> Thanks for having us.
>> You want to do an introduction?
>> Sure. What an honor. It's an honor uh
for me to be here with Sheldon and
Susan. Uh we've spent a lot of time in
Louisiana. It's our largest data center
investment uh for Meta and I've been
with them in Louisiana. And what is
remarkable to me is just the leadership
that frankly the governor has shown.
Susan is the commerce secretary for
Louisiana, the economic development um
secretary, and Sheldon uh who I'm going
to let him speak for himself, but he is
such an inspirational figure there. and
he is the one that realized that because
of our investment the tax surplus would
go straight to teachers and maybe you
can talk just a little bit about that.
>> Yes. So it's great to be here. Um I just
think back to my first interaction with
Meta. Uh it was in the summer of 2024
and um it was at our local community
college and I just remember after the
meeting getting in my car and uh it's
hot in Louisiana so I turned the air on
and I just sat there and I said the game
has changed. Um this is going to give
our parish an opportunity to do
something that it's never been able to
do. So, when the groundbreaking ceremony
happened in December of 2024,
um I could immediately start to see the
increase in our sales tax collections.
Um there are six taxing entities in our
parish. The Richland Parish School Board
collects 51% of the taxes for the
district. Um, so I was able to see the
sales tax collections go from 5% 10%
which is normal for a school system to
about 60 or 70%. And at that time the
number of workers at the data center
site increased. Um, those collections
peaked at about 260%.
That's an increase in sales tax
collections. Um, and so we have a 1 cent
and a 1/2 cent sales tax that's
dedicated to employee salaries. And so
we're announcing these sales tax
increases at our schoolboard meetings.
And we're educators, so people can do
the math.
They start to figure out this is going
to translate into a larger sales tax
check, which directly goes into our
salaries. So in December of 2025, we
gave out a 1 half cent sales tax check.
That check doubled from the previous
year. So it went from roughly about
$4,000 to about $8,000, but we hadn't
seen a full year of spiked increases in
sales tax collections. That happened
this past June. Uh, so our certified
employees received an increase of about
$40,000 in their sales tax.
>> $40,000 check.
>> They got a $50,000 check.
>> Wow.
>> So the check the previous year was
$10,000.
So if you take that December increase
and the June increase, it was a a net of
about $45,000
for our teachers.
>> Did they all Cuz the reason Dina and I
were talking about this panel and
everyone hates data centers. They pull
80 in the United States. And Dina was
telling me the story and I was like, we
should tell this story because it is
unbelievable. Did the teachers and the
community have this negative sentiment
about data centers before? Were they
all, we hate data centers, we don't want
them here or was that before this wave
happened and the community didn't really
kind of pay much attention to it?
>> I think initially there was the unknown.
Um, and we are we are the beginning.
We're a starting point. There was no
reference for us to to access. We
couldn't say, "Okay, well, when the last
time, when was the last time we had a
$50 billion capital investment in our
schools?" So, how did we handle that?
So, yeah, where, you know, a few million
dollars, that's that's that's huge for
us. So, um, there was there was anxious
thoughts. Um, I think Meta has done an
excellent job of informing us and
educating us and that's going to have to
continue to happen. Oftent times this
communication is not about the most for
informed person in the community. It's
about the least informed person in the
community. So, we're working to make
sure that we continue to get that
positive message out about the good
things that are happening because there
are a lot of good things that are
happening in our parish.
>> Yeah. I think to the superintendent's
point, um, Louisiana was a little bit
late to the data center game, which has
actually worked remarkably well to our
benefit in that the the meta investment
was the first one in the state. Um and
because of the partnership, the way um
we negotiated the deal, I call it a a
partnership, not a negotiation, frankly,
all all along. Um the community when we
first brought the idea even prior to you
knowing, superintendent, um the
community wasn't apprehensive because
there was a great deal of unknown. Now,
keep in mind this was now about 20
months ago is when we started the
conversation there. Um so, so the the
chatter wasn't as much as it is now. But
you're talking about a community that
was really starved for opportunity. As
you saw in the video, you know, we had
lost population. Uh the average wages in
Richland Parish were roughly 36 $38,000
a year prior to this investment. So, um,
the data center went to a place in
Louisiana, you know, Mississippi Delta
Parish that was Mississippi River Delta.
Obviously, it was it was longing for
this opportunity and we got ahead of
that and I think we got ahead of that
very wisely in the way we um addressed
both the concerns, the impact on the
community, um, the good impact on the
community and the natural resources and
all the things we're hearing right in a
weird way. And all of this noise is
actually somewhat beneficial in the
sense that you may just want to go to
Dena and say we'll just take all your
data centers because you can't I mean I
mean quite honestly
>> I think our governor would actually
continuous change in the in the earnings
potential of normal average Americans.
>> Yeah. We the governor just signed an
executive order a few months ago
creating a framework for us under which
we will engage with large load users.
Right. And the privilege that it gives
us now is we get to be choosy, right? We
we have a a sales tax exemption which is
critical to be able to land an
investment of this size and this scale.
But now we get to really court who our
partners are going to be and the
governor claims it all the time that
META really was the prototype for us and
it set a very high standard. Um and
that's now the standard we're going to
follow. We are not one of those states
who is saying no. Um we are one of those
states that are saying yes and
>> yeah. So
maybe you could help us with it's pretty
clear the economic case for you know
building uh and growing and creating
jobs. Take us through the list of valid
concerns communities have. One of them
is pollution. I'm not sure if this is
running off of gas or if it's all solar
and renewables. Increased electricity
cost. Water closed loop versus non-clos
loop. Noise pollution and aesthetics.
These buildings are awfully ugly
typically as created. Um, did any of
those apply? Did you get any of that
feedback from the community?
>> Our journalist.
>> What's that?
>> No, no, no. Actually, it's not
journalism. Actually, what it is is it's
facts, Saxs. These are the facts of Dina
the people. Hold on, I'll finish. Uh,
these are the facts that community
members have valid concerns about. There
are people who have had data centers put
next to them that are polluting, that
are creating noise, and there are valid
water concerns, and there are
communities where their electricity went
up. So, I'm asking a serious question
based on facts. I'm wondering if any of
those apply to you.
>> Yeah, Janie, you said this was going to
be easy. No, no, no. Um, yeah, clearly,
you know, we're all people, right? We
all hear, we all have the same concerns.
Um, again, some of it was that we got
very lucky with the timing of all this
because those issues were addressed
before they became in the public forum
of issues. You know, number one, this
was farmland. This was agricultural
land. Um, and early on in the
conversations with with the Meta team.
Um, they they made a decision to use a
more expensive but more efficient system
that actually uses less water than was
being used on that land when it was
being farmed. Right? It's not a
statistic you hear very often. The
second piece about the energy, clearly
we're we're hearing it um across the
board, but there are two really critical
components to this. Number one is that
Louisiana has abundant natural gas. We
have about 32,000 miles of natural gas
pipelines in Louisiana today if we don't
add another mile. So, we have access to
natural gas everywhere. Um but but in
the in the relationship that Meta
created with Entury, the the energy
provider there, um from day one, before
this was a an executive order from the
president or even the governor, Meta
paid for its own generation. It paid for
grid resilience. It paid for grid
upgrades. It paid for storm costs.
Louisiana has storm assessments when we
have hurricanes. It happens every now
and then. It's paying for storm costs in
a state where they didn't operate right
when these hurricanes hit. So, it's
actually taking burdens off of the
Louisiana consumer. Um, so all those
issues were issues and they were
addressed with the original um
negotiated deal. And I will say it's
really why it's become the prototype for
how we move forward with others.
>> This is a question for you. You used to
be the deputy national security adviser.
So answer this maybe with just a bit of
that hat on. I mean Jason brings up
valid concerns but then there's this
data that is so clear for you but also
for others. I mean you just heard from
Satya. Why is this misinformation
campaign winning so soundly in America?
>> What has happened? Like what is going
on?
>> Sure. Well, I think first the questions
that Jason raised are really legitimate
questions. And I think we start with a
premise that if a community doesn't want
one of our data centers, they get to
choose. They get to decide. But that we
actually have to upfront and way more
aggressively explain what our investment
and partnership means. And we have a
compact, a compact that Susan and
Sheldon are describing. First, not just
pay for your own electricity. Make sure
that you're working to drive electricity
costs down. The second is the water
issue. It's very real in farmlands and
rural communities, but there's
absolutely now new technology, in fact,
AIdriven technology that makes you able
to uh actually increase water
consumption. The third is the teachers.
I'll be very honest, this was not our
idea. This actually happened because
this law uh allows or in fact mandates
that every extra dollar of tax surplus
goes directly to the teachers and the
superintendent was telling me things
that just are so remarkable. Used to
have a hard time recruiting teachers.
Now his phone is ringing off the hook
throughout Louisiana. Teachers wanting
to come there and this may end up being
the best school district um in the
entire state. And now we have taken that
learning and we're investing in teachers
and first responders. And you saw of
course the economic development impact
for small businesses. That's our compact
everywhere we go. Meta um makes sure
that we makes sure that we do those
things. But to answer your question,
Shimoth, I don't think that our industry
has done a good job communicating just
just flat out we have to do a better
job. But before you can communicate
anything, you've actually got to be
meaningful and have real impact. And so
we've started with the premise that we
want to be the best actor and the best
partner possible. and now having frankly
the impact that we see in Louisiana.
We're very proud of the impact we're
having in Texas and Ohio, but I think we
have to tell these stories more. And I
know you're alluding to where is this
information coming from? You know, I was
just with um Chairman Cotton and Vice
Chairman Mark Warner and the
intelligence committees. You know, they
do believe they have evidence that our
adversaries are trying to jin this up. I
can't comment on that, but what I can
tell you is if you wanted to stop
America right now, what would you do?
This is exactly what you would try to
do. if you were any of our adversaries,
you would want us to stop building data
centers in the United States so that we
could uh you know, we we would not be on
a path to being AI uh dominant in the
world. This is what you would do. So
whether they're doing it or not, this is
definitely an approach you would take.
And I I actually said to them very
respectfully, these are great jobs and
the communities that want the jobs, want
the teacher bonuses, want these
investments should be allowed to have
them. and those that don't should opt
out. But we certainly don't want uh our
companies, our my company and our peers
to start thinking about building data
centers.
>> It's so easy to debunk these issues. The
water one is the one that just
confounding that confounding that that
narrative keeps staying alive. I think
you did an amazing job.
>> There's a clip on X of this woman with
this bottle of dirty water that she
trucks around and and you're just like
>> so good.
>> There's there's there's no
>> You know what? You know what I love? I
love that it's a federated republic that
the founders designed and some states
are going to win, some states are going
to be idiots and they're going to lose
and you know, you guys are going to have
this incredible economic advantage.
>> Yeah, I do want to add to to Dena's
point as well, just as the teachers are
calling Sheldon to consider going to his
parish to teach. The minute that got
announced um that y'all were giving
$50,000 bonuses, I can't tell you how
many leaders of rural parishes in
Louisiana called me and said,
"Secretary, do do y'all have any who are
considering our parish? Please bring one
here." So, so the global narrative is
not happening in Louisiana. I frankly, I
don't believe it's happening everywhere
the way the propaganda
>> calling you from across the country like
other states saying, "Is this real? How
did this work?" and starting to kind of
lean in and see if they can participate.
>> So, historically, one of the challenges
we've had as a rural school system is
that our best and our brightest will
they they'll they'll do exceptionally
well in school. They may even go to our
local universities, but but when they
leave, I have a good idea in my head
that they're not coming back to Richland
Parish because we can't offer jobs that
that attract them. So they they leave
and they go to other states and they go
to other cities. And now we're able to
to to write our own narrative that if
you want to leave and go, you can, but
you don't have to. We have opportunity
here for you here in Richland Parish.
You have the ability to stay here to
raise your family. And I think it's
changing the narrative in our parish.
Well, Dina, I know you've got another
video for us to watch also on um how do
we get more workers to come and
participate in this growing economy. Um
while we watch that, why don't we thank
Susan and Sheldon for joining us. Thank
you both for being here. Thank you so
much.
>> Thank you very much. Yeah, that was
great. Fantas
Thank you so much. Appreciate you very
much. Appreciate you coming out. Thank
you so much.
>> I've always wanted to do something big.
I know that this is the program that I
need to be in in order to discover that.
>> In order for a lot of technology to
advance, we need the infrastructure.
Meta is blessing these guys with the
opportunity to be a part of that to help
lay foundation for the future.
>> You can come into the program with no
prior experience after you finish your
four weeks here, be able to go into the
workforce.
I'm grateful for this opportunity. I'm
excited to actually get to do the work.
>> To have a group of students who are
taking the opportunity serious and are
doing it with passion, that means
everything.
>> Once they're able to finish our course,
there's so many different paths that
they can take. The more that we learn
and establish this workforce, the more
we can impact future generations.
>> I feel like it will change the world.
I'm ready to work.
you were telling me a story about like a
posting for fiber optic technician. Can
you just tell that story because I think
it's incredible. Sure.
>> So, um, even in our site in Louisiana,
one of the issues is that we just can't
find enough workers and you really need
a set of obviously welders and pipe
fitters and construction workers,
electricians. Uh but there's something
that every data center site really needs
fiber technicians, the people that just
actually lay and cut the fiber. And we
just could not find enough people. And
so we just made a curriculum and we
partnered with a few people CBRE and
others. And uh we realized that this
program just didn't exist. So we decided
if you can do it for fiber technicians,
why not go beyond? It's a fiveweek
fasttrack training program where you get
all of your safety training. You get uh
designated something called job site
ready. So you can get the job. We at
Meta guarantee you a job if you graduate
on one of our data center sites and you
have that certification with you whether
you want to stay at our site or
elsewhere. And the missing piece is that
while there are, as David Saxs has said
over and over again, there are 500,000
open jobs for these uh roles over the
next couple of years, but there was this
gap between people actually getting
those jobs. And it's because it turns
out if you're a waitress or you're an
Uber driver or you are a home healthare
worker, you live paycheck to paycheck.
You cannot afford to take that time time
off unpaid. The training is weirdly very
expensive. OSHA training and things like
that. And what if you do that and you
don't get a job? So we launched
America's Workforce Academy. Uh we
launched it I don't know four months
ago. 40,000 Americans applied. We've
graduated 250 people
>> and we have a 90% retention rate. So
people that are getting into these
contractor jobs uh on our data center
sites um you can see they've learned a
new trade, they've left behind a job
that wasn't as fulfilling and that of
course every company that's hiring them
um is just thrilled. It's also something
that's interesting, David, that you and
I talked about, which is we um have
partners across the board in this
program. We called we didn't put META in
the name because we are so excited to be
working with other companies that are
interested in recruiting these workers
as well. Um, but we're working with the
unions. Sean McGarvey, uh, the head of
the trades, NABU, um, is a friend and we
made a great partnership with him there.
Some of those workers are on union
sites, some are non-union. But an
interesting voice that has emerged in
this debate is the unions. The union
leadership now is saying, "We want to be
anti- the anti-data center backlash.
These are our jobs. These are for our
people." And so they actually put out
even before the midterms um a note
saying they are only going to support
candidates that support data centers.
>> How much uh balance
the big how much balance sheet capital
does it take to get this thing off the
ground and do you see the other majors
the big eight kind of joining forces and
having this new educational track kind
of become a deacto standard in America?
>> You know all of us are working on this.
In fact, I just talked to Ruth Porat at
Google. She's done an incredible job um
on workforce and she's actually brought
together uh we're we're going to join
this alliance. Larry Frink at BlackRock
has joined the alliance. She's bringing
together other companies. You know, we
we might uh you know, might compete on
models and products, but we don't want
to compete on people. We we as an
industry, I think, are doing this part
well where we're really working together
because anybody that gets trained to
work on a metadata center site can
certainly go to a Google site or a
Microsoft site. And so this is a place
where we've really come together.
>> How do you how do you expand the
capacity? So there's 40,000 that
applied, but you picked 400.
>> Yeah.
>> That's 39,600 that
>> Yeah. And and and we started 4 months
ago and now uh we're literally getting
calls from Mary Bar at GM. I'll I'd like
a thousand employees, you know, once you
have the curriculum and the
certification and the partners to
deliver it. Uh you can do these
everywhere. We're doing them in
community colleges, VFW halls. In that
particular program, you actually have to
have a site that's kind of like a model
data center so that you can show how to
train the fiber technicians. But we're
working with the Association of Builders
and Contractors. They have, you know,
thousands and thousands of of uh places
across the country where they operate.
>> Why why is it so expensive outside of
you guys basically backstopping this to
get something like job site ready and
OSHA awareness? I mean this should seem
like you go online and
>> I think the thing that we unlocked is
that we actually pay during the training
what you would get if you are already in
the job. It used to be that there's a
very low fee or an apprentice fee for so
long that it wasn't you know it wasn't
the full pay payment of the job. And so
we do that from the beginning. Um, and
then of course these jobs. I mean, David
and I've been in Pittsburgh with with uh
some of these workers and you know,
these are jobs. Welders make $120,000 a
year in Pittsburgh. That is meaningful
great work. And I think the unlock that
we're very proud of with this program is
that there just wasn't a clear and fast
path to getting on the job site and to
having a guaranteed job.
>> It's great that you have these jobs
because with AI progressing so quickly,
these developers are going to need
something to do. And so I think they can
segue into electrician jobs. I'm kidding
obviously. Uh but absolutely fantastic
work on the data centers. Fully
supported. Great job on the meta
glasses. Amazing. And and this effort
>> Where are your metagasses, Jason? I gave
you such
>> They're right here on the bag. I right
in my backpack. Uh they're they're No,
they're actually u super impressive. And
this effort
>> this effort is truly impressive. But you
said you wanted me to do a fast ball or
two. Uh, and you you didn't want it to
be
>> She didn't say that. Jal,
>> she literally asked me for at least one
one fast.
>> Jal fast ball. Uh,
>> you did. Okay, so we'll just keep it all
softball before you ask question.
Please, please come back.
>> Go ahead, Jason.
>> No, no, no. We can just go. We'll go
softballs. The boys prefer. Go ahead. Go
ahead. Well, I mean, we we have meta
here and you just paid the largest
settlement in second only to the tobacco
industry. Uh, and just ahead of BP oil,
u, two of the biggest disasters this
country ever faced. And this one is
particularly tough
>> and they wonder why they call him fake
news.
>> Um
uh no I I I numbers are wrong. I'm I'm
happy to talk about the meta glasses if
you prefer.
>> I'm so glad
go read your effective altruism.
>> I'm actually really glad you asked me
about it because
>> yeah well no let me finish the question.
You you may not be
>> um so
uh I'm going to lean in now so to speak.
Um
the the real I think challenge a lot of
us have with Facebook as an organization
and and these are amazing. The videos
are super inspiring and well produced.
But you guys really did damage
significant damage to children. You knew
that these products were too addicting.
And the philosophy of the company from
the beginning when Shamath was there,
hey, move fast, break things, let's go
super fast. My my my sincere question is
how has the culture changed inside of
Facebook and you're making a new series
of potentially more addicting products
with character-based AI companions with
Muse as a product. So I'm curious what's
changed in the organization and what did
you learn from that record setting find
and something that is you could have
done a lot better on.
>> Um well I totally disagree with
basically every single premise in your
question.
>> Totally fine.
billion dollar settlement says
otherwise.
>> Do I get to speak or are you done with
your 10-minute question? Um, okay. I
totally disagree with the premise of
that.
>> I've only been there eight months. I was
on the board for a year and I can tell
you cuz I work with these people every
day. They are really, really focused on
ensuring that parents are empowered,
teens are supported. And I couldn't be
actually more proud of the agreement
that we just uh we just made. We made it
with 52 bipartisan attorneys general
across the United States and the
territories. We are now setting industry
standards. Uh we agreed that if uh your
state signed on with us that uh children
under 18, not 16, can only be on our
platform for 2 hours a day. The app
shuts off after that and it completely
shops shuts off at night. Uh there are
no notifications during the school day
at all of any kind. And frankly, parents
have way more supervision now. Uh many,
many ways that they can decide what
their kids are on, how long they're on,
and what they're seeing. And I think
that we're proud of that because if
others in our peer group joined, this
could be pretty historic and
gamechanging. And Jason, I'm a mom of
six daughters, so this is really
personal to me. I watched them grow up
in this in this generation, and I feel
that, you know, we really can actually
find a way to come together. Um, the
reason your numbers were wrong on the
settlement is because we actually agreed
to give an additional $5 billion and to
go down to only one hour of use on our
platform if YouTube, Tik Tok, and Snap
join us because, as we know,
as we know, people leave one set of apps
and go to another. But wouldn't it be
pretty amazing in America if children
under 18 could only be on apps for an
hour a day, shut off at night? And I
don't I just think that's
>> 100% yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Do you think do you think it should be
universal chimoth or do you think it
should be controlled by the parent like
give the parent basic controls? What's
your view?
>> Well, it is meaning obviously a parent
can override it but our app actually
just does turn off.
>> Obviously a parent. It's funny. I was in
Texas this weekend at the Texas uh Ohio
State game. you
my alma mater. And um and it was really
funny. I had so many uh people come up
to me and say, you know, you know this
turning off because it it's literally
happening. Turning off Instagram is
hurting college uh college recruiting,
football recruiting. I'm like, what?
What are you talking about? In Texas, we
put all of our kids videos on Instagram
and they get recruited. So, it is
interesting. I said, well, we live in
America. That's up to you. You can
decide as a parent if you want to do
more. that it does actually shut off and
a parent has to override that.
>> I think I think it's incredible. I
remember just being with my kids at the
dinner table and my son was trying to
show me something and he had hit the
limit just turned off and there's
nothing and I was like this is
fantastic. You're like leave it off.
Like
>> what's that?
>> You're like just leave it off. You don't
care.
>> The reason is as a parent it's
whack-a-ole.
>> Yeah.
>> Because the content is syndicated across
all these platforms. And that's why what
you're saying is so right. When my son
when my kids, my five kids go to school,
they interact with YouTube as their
primary outside of school mechanism
because so much of the school content
and educational content is there. So
even if you shut off shorts and
Instagram, they pop up over here.
>> So it is this whack-a-ole problem for
parents and you you it's a full-time job
to manage it. And so if there is
effectively like a labeling and like you
know a decision on governance by these
companies, it's deeply helpful for all
of us that have jobs are trying to live
a life and raise kids normally so they
don't become zombies.
>> Zach, you're very active managing your
kids mobile phone usage.
>> Yeah. How many do you have?
>> Look, I um I I think the new defaults
probably are better. I mean, just
thinking about my kids usage, yeah, it'd
be nice if it turned off after, you
know, an hour or two. Um, so yeah, look,
I think that's that's an improvement. I
I do have to sort of def defend Meta
because I do think that there was a
little bit of a ridiculous pylon um
where, you know, the company's getting
sued by adults who are blaming the use
of this completely voluntary product. No
one's forcing you to use any of these
social network products and then
something goes wrong in their life that
has many causes and then they're suing
Meta and winning big judgments and then
the state ags get in on the act and all
the trial lawyers
>> and the trial lawyers the trial lawyers
money I thought.
>> Yeah. So, so let's just acknowledge that
there is a little bit of a shakeddown
going on here as well. I mean let's face
it that that is kind of how the American
uh court system works. But look, I think
that they have reached a resolution that
I think is net beneficial and I like the
new defaults and ultimately this is
about parental control. You know,
parents should choose what you know and
how what apps their kids use and for how
long. It should not be the government
doing that. It should be the parents.
>> Dina, can you
>> and we should just make it as easy as
possible for the parents to do it. And
in my view, the only reason to do these
new defaults is because of the
whack-a-mole problem. It is sometimes
difficult for the to like
>> I mean that is I'm glad we're having
this discussion. Um I I think the issue
for me has been the industry got very
addicted to gamification and designing
products to be addicting and increasing
time spent on app was in fact internally
what Facebook was focused on. The
challenge is, you know, you can be too
good at something and I think Facebook
along with YouTube and their algorithm
were just too good at addicting people
to it, whether they're adults or kids.
And I will commend you even if it was
late as an organization in doing the
right thing now and then leading the
other organizations to do the right
thing.
>> Let me build on what you were saying
with the statement. Um, and we Satia
talked about this. I think Jensen will
talk about it. Elon will talk about it.
But we are you're going to hear this
word RSI over and over over the next 18
months. recursive self-improvement,
which is this idea that if you define a
function, a reward function for an AI
and let it go, it's going to
self-improve. So, to your point, Jason,
anything, whether it's, you know, World
of Warcraft or Angry Birds or whatever
app, you put it into an RSI loop and you
add the reward function being time,
they all these apps will proliferate.
Microsoft Word will keep you there for 9
hours if it can. So if unless companies
make a decision like you guys to say
here's a threshold and beyond this
threshold we're just going to turn it
off. It's going to be kind of turtles
all
>> which was my point is how does it inform
product decisions going forward? You got
this incredible new product muse. You're
you're you're in the mix on the bots. Um
but again I think the leadership and
challenging the other organizations is
what I will give you kudos for.
>> You know I don't want to speculate. I I
want to talk about this this this this
addiction thing as it relates to the
product that we all tried on backstage.
We all put on a meta glass and I'd never
um I've never had the product before.
What is the the repeated use case of
that product you think? Like what is it
that gets people cuz you know Yeah. The
glasses. Sorry. Yeah. So like I remember
when Google had the goggles and then
Apple had VR and everyone's had an
effort at putting something on your face
and none of them have stickiness.
They're all like really interesting
novelty experiences and then your usage
tapers off and you kind of put it in the
drawer and it's like a cool tech relic.
>> Well, they're very stylish.
>> Yeah,
>> these are the Kylie Jenners. Um, no,
actually we are so excited about this as
a product. Um, the the engineers have
been working on this for 10 years. Um,
you make a good point that if people
don't look good in them and they're not
stylish, they're not going to put them
on. But, you know, billions of people
wear glasses, whether they're to see uh
or obviously sunglasses. And we're
really excited about the features. You
can obviously listen to music. Uh the
only way I listen to Allin every week is
wearing my meta glasses as I'm walking
or working out. Uh they actually have
the incredible speaker and so your your
phone calls are perfect. Uh and now we
have a couple of features we're really
excited about. Conversation focus. So
when Chamath is uh you know at dinner
with his beautiful wife and he actually
wants to hear her if he looks at her all
the noise uh it goes away except her
voice which is pretty cool. Um and then
translation.
>> That's great translation as well.
>> Can I do the opposite when I'm
>> Shimath? It's interesting Dina. It's
interesting you bring this up Dina.
>> Great
people I talk to. I'd like more of that.
>> Shimath is just telling me he got the
new Apple AirPods 5 specifically because
of wife cancelling.
>> The opposite. want the opposite feature.
>> You can actually tune in. But let me
tell you why you're wrong and I'm right.
Okay, thanks.
>> By the way, with with these products,
you're, you know, you're you're damned
if you do and damned if you don't in the
sense that if you design it poorly, no
one's going to want to use it. If you
design it really well and it's a big
success, a bunch of trial lawyers are
going to say it was addictive and then
you get sued for that.
>> So true.
>> Dina, can you Sorry, I just wanted to
move to AI for a second before
>> No, I want to finish on this. So like so
but but but it has this kind of
recurrent use case built into it at this
point. Is that cuz I really want to
understand if
>> the reason so many people are are
working I mean all of our peers are
working on wearables because I do think
people want to be part of the world.
They actually don't want to be holding
boxes walking around. They actually
really want to be able to talk to their
family, take a picture, take a video, um
listen to music and it be hands-free. We
have Oakleys uh that are really really
cool for um extreme sports. So, the use
cases are just everyday life. And I
think you're going to show a video. The
thing that surprised us was one use case
that we hadn't anticipated, and that uh
blind veterans. Um, actually, somebody
uh was joking with me. They said, um,
how are you getting blind people to wear
glasses? That doesn't make sense to me.
But can we show this video? It is such
an honor to be here. We're in Austin,
Texas at a BFW hall where metamates are
sitting down with amazing men and women
who've served our country and who lost
their eyesight. They have just been
telling us they feel like they're
getting their independence back and
we're so proud to be giving them meta
glasses.
>> I took them to church. They have the
scriptures on the screen in front. I've
never been able to read that, but I
asked Meta and it read it word for word
for me.
>> Seeing these extraordinary servicemen
and women, all we've been saying is
thank you. Thank you. We don't have
America without all of them. And as a
big surprise, uh we are about to
introduce them to Chris Stapleton. just
want to come by and say thank you for
all your service. We're so grateful for
you.
>> Chris Stapleton's the best.
>> He he came and joined us. It was
actually on 911 and uh just a couple
days ago. And what we learned is that um
a group of uh blind veterans from uh the
organization that that supports them
came and actually worked with the meta
engineers and designed specific
features. And it just turns out
obviously the glasses can see for you
and read read to you. One of the
gentlemen I was sitting next to put the
glasses on and he said, "Hey Meta, call
John." And I was sitting there, I
couldn't hear obviously what he was
hearing and he just started sobbing. And
I said, "Is everything okay, sir?" He
said, "That's the first time I've ever
called my son on my own independently."
>> Wow.
>> So, we're seeing these kinds of use
cases, of course, that we're incredibly
proud of.
>> I guess AI AI creates the unlock for the
glass form factor. That makes a lot of
sense. I because
>> is that the form factor that you think
kind of gets AI in a prevalent way for
most people in the world is the glasses
form factor or is there something else
you think
>> I'm I'm sure there will be many
products. I mean I I think what I have
learned from our team um is that you
know glasses are a thing people wear
glasses and it's something that you know
many many people they're affordable and
people obviously we really worked hard.
Mark was very focused not just on the
design but the weight of it. So takes a
lot to put the technology in here and to
still keep it stylish. And
>> I think you're a minority owner of
Rayban. No. Or of looks like the broad
partner. Yeah. We have an exclusive with
>> I think that's why people should
reconsider these, you know, as a product
category cuz I've had them since Google
Glass. And the battery never worked.
They were too bulky. You look like a
dork in them. And now the battery works
and because you can control them, you
know, not with Siri, which is still kind
of broken, but this actually works. And
when you're with your kids and you want
to take videos when you're skiing or you
want to take pictures, it actually, you
know, putting a phone between you is is
much more intrusive. So, I think this
actually brings you into the real world.
And the translation feature is also very
slick. So, when you go to Japan or you
go somewhere and they're talking to you
in another language, it can actually
translate. or if you see a sign, boom,
just instant translation without taking
your phone out. It's time for people to
reconsider these um specifically for
those reasons.
>> Yeah.
>> You've used them a long time though, so
you really know.
>> Yeah. The batteries, the battery
problem, the fidelity just they didn't
work and now it does. Yeah. So,
>> Dina, just talking about the Dario's
essay this weekend, there was a report,
but it was unverified that Zach said
something to the effect of we need to go
as fast as we can. Um, I don't know if
that was kind of misinformation. No, no,
it was like a report that just hit
Twitter at the same time that Daario's
or X when Daario hang out, but just
taking a step back broadly, how did you
process that essay and the call for
regulation or how are you guys thinking
about this?
>> Sure. Well, first I I really agree with
a lot of what Satcha said. I mean, the
the the premise, the starting point is
that safety is paramount and that is
something that Mark talks about all the
time. I watch um daily how he and Alex
Wang and Natt Friedman who run our lab
think about it and they're and a whole
team of people exist to think about the
safety of the models. Um and I and I
think that you know there are very
legitimate questions around that. I
think the difference is that Mark just
has a very different view and I think
that view is based on 20 years of a
business model of empowering and
connecting people and that 3.6 6 billion
people are on our platform every single
day. 200 million small business owners
operate their business every single day.
And so his belief is that the more you
distribute this technology, the more
people that have super intelligence and
are able to reach their potential are
able to have access to education and
health care that they could have never
imagined before, learning that they
could have never achieved before is not
only better for each of those
individuals, but it's better for society
as a whole. So he fundamentally just
believes when he wrote in his piece the
future is for everyone that the
democratization of artificial
intelligence will actually lead to a
more stable society. That is just a
fundamental belief that he has and I
think that um the thing that he thinks
about is so then what is his role? What
is our role? And I think we were
extremely proud to have the very first
American open-source model
>> just a few weeks ago. Well, Dina, you've
uh got a lot on your plate. We really
appreciate you taking the time to come
and join us today. We covered a lot. It
was awesome. Thank you for being here.
>> Thank you guys so much. Thank you so
much.
Thank you. You're welcome. That was
great.